{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "83_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Can you enter the exhibition hall now?\nMan : Please wait a moment. Entry will start soon.\nWoman : Yes. I got it",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "83_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Oh, it's heavy, where should I put this flower pot?\nMan : How about in front of the window here?\nWoman : Yes. That would be good",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "83_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : The purpose of foreign tourists visiting Korea was 'vacation' the most. Next were 'business' and 'visiting relatives'. Then, who will foreign tourists come to Korea with? 'Family or friends' accounted for the most at 54%, 'alone' accounted for 33%, and 'colleers' accounted for 10%.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  어제 다 읽었어.",
            "option_2"      : "②  천천히 읽고 돌려줘.",
            "option_3"      : "③  책 읽을 시간이 없었어.",
            "option_4"      : "④  재미있는 책 좀 추천해 줘.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : 미수야, are you reading the book I lent you? Is it fun.\nMan : Yes, it's fun. But until when can I return it?\nWoman : Read it slowly and return it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  천천히 읽고 돌려줘.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  그래요? 한번 가 봐야겠어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그럼요. 내일부터 일하기로 했어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  정말요? 힘들면 언제든지 그만두세요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  맞아요. 좋은 곳을 구해서 기분이 좋아요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : I still haven't found a part-time job.\nWoman : They were looking for someone to work in the restaurant in front of the school.\nMan : Really? I should go.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  그래요? 한번 가 봐야겠어요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  그럼 하얀색으로 바꾸러 가자.",
            "option_2"      : "②  나는 다른 운동화도 신어 볼래.",
            "option_3"      : "③  새로 산 운동화가 마음에 들어.",
            "option_4"      : "④  파란색이 너한테 더 잘 어울려.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I want to do it with these sneakers. What should I buy? \nMan : I like both blue and white, what's better?\nWoman : Blue looks better on you.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  파란색이 너한테 더 잘 어울려.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  비가 곧 그칠 거래요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  일기 예보를 볼 걸 그랬어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  장마가 끝나니까 진짜 더워요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  작년하고 거의 비슷할 거래요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I saw on the news that the rainy season starts on the weekend.\nMan : Is that so? Will it rain as much as last year?\nWoman : It's almost the same as last year.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  작년하고 거의 비슷할 거래요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  곧 배송된다니 다행이에요. ",
            "option_2"      : "②  제품에 문제가 있는 것 같아요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  언제쯤 배송될지 확인해 주시겠어요?",
            "option_4"      : "④  고객 센터 전화번호 좀 알려 주실래요?",
            "detail"        : "Man : This is the customer center, right? I ordered a chair a week ago but it hasn't come yet.\nWoman : I'm sorry. The delivery is being delayed due to the large number of orders.\nMan : Can you check when it will be delivered?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  언제쯤 배송될지 확인해 주시겠어요?",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  사과를 씻는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  과일을 자른다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  설탕을 가져온다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  냄비를 찾아온다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I washed all the apples. I can cut it now.\nMan : I'll cut it, so do you want to do a pot there?\nWoman : Here you are. But you'll need more sugar to make a jab. Do you want me to come back?\nMan : Yes. Get me some",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  설탕을 가져온다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  모자를 벗는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  놀이 기구에 탄다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  떨어진 물건을 줍는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자에게 가방을 받는다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sir, would you like to take the ride? Would you like to keep your bag here?\nWoman : Yes. Here. Can I wear a hat and ride it?\nMan : It can fly away, so I'll keep it with you. Woman: Okay.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  모자를 벗는다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  세탁물을 넣는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  안내문을 읽는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  동전을 바꾸러 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  세탁 코스를 선택한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : It's my first time at the laundromat, can I choose the course first and put in the new water?\nMan : Here's a notice. After putting in the laundry, choose the course, and put in the coin.\nWoman : I don't have any coins. Oh, there's a coin changer over there. I'll change it.\nMan : Yes. I'll read about what else to do.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  동전을 바꾸러 간다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  거울을 치운다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  카메라를 설치한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  카메라 화면을 본다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  촬영할 물건을 가져온다.",
            "detail"        : "Female : Director, we're ready to shoot. We've put things in place.\nMan : So let's see what it looks like on the camera screen. Well, do we really need that mirror?\nFemale : The mirror is so big that it doesn't look like an office. Should I clean it up?\nMan: Yes, please.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  거울을 치운다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  두 사람은 모형 배를 만드는 중이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 모형 배는 가죽으로 만들어졌다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 남자가 준 사진을 보고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 이 모형 배를 직접 본 적이 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Do you want to see this picture? This is a model It's the same as the actual ship, right?\n Man : Wow, it's really well made. But what did you make it with? Is it a tree.\nWoman : No. It's made of leather.\nMan : It's amazing. To make a ship model using leather. I want to see it in person.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  이 모형 배는 가죽으로 만들어졌다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  개회식은 대회장에서 열린다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  대회의 장면을 찍을 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  예선 경기는 두 시에 시작된다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  개회식 후에 대기실로 가야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Female : Here's our guide to the dance competition. The opening ceremony will be held shortly from 2 o'clock. Participants in the waiting room are asked to come to the venue. As soon as the opening ceremony is over, the preliminary competition will begin, so please wait there. We can't film during the event, so we ask for your cooperation.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  개회식은 대회장에서 열린다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 사고는 오전에 발생했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  등산 객들은 모두 구조되었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고 발생 원인을 조사할 예정이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  산 정상에 오다가 사고가 발생했다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : At 10 o'clock last night, four hikers who lost their way at Mt. Inju were rescued. Rescuers who received a rescue call from hikers immediately began their search and found all of them in two hours. It was confirmed that the climbers got lost because it was dark while walking down from the top of the mountain.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  등산 객들은 모두 구조되었다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 전문적으로 그림을 배웠다. ",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자의 그림은 화려한 느낌을 준다. ",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 화가가 된 지 70년이 넘었다. ",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 평범한 것을 그림의 소재로 삼는다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : What do you think is the reason why the author's painting is gaining popularity?\nWoman : Is it because it's common and warmly painted on the material of our side? I wanted to remember my happy childhood, so I didn't start painting until I was over 70. Of course I haven't even learned. I think people like that undecorated feeling.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자는 평범한 것을 그림의 소재로 삼는다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  메일을 자주 확인해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  답장이 올 때까지 기다리는 게 낫다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  메일을 받은 사실을 알려 줘야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  답장을 보내기 전에 확인하는 게 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : 수미야, didn't you get the mail I sent you?\nWoman : No, I got it. I didn't reply yet because I was thinking about how to write it.\nMan : I was worried that the mail didn't go. You should have told me that you received it when you waited.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  메일을 받은 사실을 알려 줘야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  공부는 매일 하는 것이 중요하다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  공부하는 장소를 바꿀 필요가 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  새벽에 일어나서 공부하는 게 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  피곤할 때는 적당한 휴식도 필요하다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : I woke up early in the morning these days and I can concentrate well.\nWoman : Is that so? I think I'll be very tired when I wake up at dawn.\nMan : I was a little tired at first, but now I like my studying well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  새벽에 일어나서 공부하는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "① 다양한 분야의 사람을 만나야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "② 직업을 자주 바꾸는 것은 좋지 않다.",
            "option_3"      : "③ 같이 일하는 사람과 잘 지내야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④ 진로에 대해 충분히 고민할 필요가 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The meeting program with professional people you went to last time, was it really good?\nMan : Yes. It was so nice to hear the stories of people with various jobs.\nWoman : That's right. It was also quite helpful in deciding on a career path.\nMan : I think there's a lot to learn when you meet people in many fields.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① 다양한 분야의 사람을 만나야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  오래된 지명을 새롭게 바꿀 필요가 있다. ",
            "option_2"      : "②  지명은 많은 사람이 알기 쉽게 만들어야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  지명에 쓰인 아름다운 옛말이 사용되면 좋겠다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  지명을 만들 때는 마을의 문화를 반영해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Teacher, do you have a special opportunity to publish a book about the name of the village?\nMan : Yes. There are a lot of old words left in the place name that I don't use now. In particular, there are many beautiful expressions among the words that refer to the culture and nature of the village. I wrote a book with the hope that those expressions would come back into our daily lives and be used in various parts of our lives.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  지명에 쓰인 아름다운 옛말이 사용되면 좋겠다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  설문 조사의 주제를 바꿔야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  설문 조사는 결과 분석이 중요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  설문 조사의 계획을 잘 세워야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  설문 조사는 응답자 수가 많을수록 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Professor, this is my research plan. Can you take a look at it?\nMan : `Personality and destination`, so you want to find out how personality can end up deciding where to go? The subject is very new and good. I chose a survey as my research method, but it has little accuracy. The survey needs to be clear about what you're trying to do, so you need to be careful about what you're researching and what you're trying to do.\nWoman : Yes, but I don't know what to start with.\nMan: So start by dividing the calligraphy and the brotherhood of the destination.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  설문 조사의 계획을 잘 세워야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 연구 계획서를 작성하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 성격에 대한 연구를 하려고 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 연구 방법을 아직 결정하지 못했다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 여자의 연구 주제가 새롭다고 생각한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Professor, this is my research plan. Can you take a look at it?\nMan : `Personality and destination`, so you want to find out how personality can end up deciding where to go? The subject is very new and good. I chose a survey as my research method, but it has little accuracy. The survey needs to be clear about what you're trying to do, so you need to be careful about what you're researching and what you're trying to do.\nWoman : Yes, but I don't know what to start with.\nMan: So start by dividing the calligraphy and the brotherhood of the destination.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  남자는 여자의 연구 주제가 새롭다고 생각한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자가 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  취업에 성공한 방법을 소개하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  신입 사원 연수 일정을 변경하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  신입 사원 채용 절차를 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  입사 전에 해야 할 일을 안내하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello, this is Boss Inju. I sent a text message to the successful applicants for the health check-up and the training schedule for new employees, did you check it?\nWoman : Yes. I checked it. By the way, does the health check-up only need to be done at the hospital that has been delivered?\nMan : No. You can go to a health center or hospital near your home and get it. You can pay the results of the examination before you go to work after the training. During the training of new employees, you only need to submit the middle name by text message.\nWoman : Thank you. Then I'll see you at the training.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  입사 전에 해야 할 일을 안내하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 회사의 신입 사원 연수가 끝났다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  신입 사원 연수 일정을 문자로 공지했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  건강 검진은 정해진 병원에서 받아야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  건강 검진 결과는 출근 후에 제출하면 된다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello, this is Boss Inju. I sent a text message to the successful applicants for the health check-up and the training schedule for new employees, did you check it?\nWoman : Yes. I checked it. By the way, does the health check-up only need to be done at the hospital that has been delivered?\nMan : No. You can go to a health center or hospital near your home and get it. You can pay the results of the examination before you go to work after the training. During the training of new employees, you only need to submit the middle name by text message.\nWoman : Thank you. Then I'll see you at the training.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  신입 사원 연수 일정을 문자로 공지했다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  타이어를 설계할 때는 환경을 생각해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  생산된 타이어의 저장 공간을 마련해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  운전자의 의견을 타이어 디자인에 반영해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  타이어의 재료로 쓸 새로운 소재를 연구해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I heard that the tire you designed this time will be on sale soon. In what ways is it different from the existing tires?\nMan : I thought that for environmental protection, changes were needed in the existing tire design that only emphasized performance. The small plastics from the tires are designed to be the biggest cause of contamination and are designed to be stored in a capsule device inside the tire without flying away. When the capsule was full, the color of the side of the tire changed so that the driver could know.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  타이어를 설계할 때는 환경을 생각해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 타이어는 많은 판매량을 기록했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 타이어의 안쪽에는 특수한 장치가 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 타이어는 성능 향상에 중점을 두고 개발되었다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 타이어는 대기 오염의 정도를 색깔로 알려 준다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I heard that the tire you designed this time will be on sale soon. In what ways is it different from the existing tires?\nMan : I thought that for environmental protection, changes were needed in the existing tire design that only emphasized performance. The small plastics from the tires are designed to be the biggest cause of contamination and are designed to be stored in a capsule device inside the tire without flying away. When the capsule was full, the color of the side of the tire changed so that the driver could know.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  이 타이어의 안쪽에는 특수한 장치가 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
        
    ]
   
}
